

Peter C. Mwita

An IT Support Specialist with a passion of using My Technological Know how to solve IT related issues. Skilled in computer hardware support issues, Network Administration & support, web design & development with proficiency in JavaScript, Php, Html / css, JavaScript Frameworks, laravel and CMS like WordPress and Joomla among other additional skills



Nairobi, Kenya https://pmwita.github.io/ in



Work Experience



ICT Digital Literacy Program Intern (DLP Officer) • Ministry of Education

October 2021 - Present

Duties and Responsibilities

- . Support of E-Learning and content development in line with the schemes of work
- . Providing classroom support and training OF School teachers in use of digital literacy devices
- . Support implementation of the Digital Literacy Programme
- . Carrying out innovations to enable schools improve on use of digital learning
- . Provide support in safe, secure and ethical use of technology in learning
- . Assist teachers by integrating ICT in delivery of teaching, learning, assessment and reporting
- . Support school staff with development and production of key school policies and procedures
- . Provide first line support and maintenance of ICT services in the schools
- . Any other duty that may be assigned by the Sub County Director of



Technical Support Assistant • Safetrac Limited

October 2020 - March 2021

Duties and Responsibilities

Support field technicians on installations, checks and troubleshooting of Telematics Devices Upload changes on platform as directed by TM

Support office IT

Train staff on office IT

Configure all devices (IOT or Telematics devices)

Test all new devices (IOT Tracking or Telematics devices)

Train staff and Clients on solutions as assigned by Technical Managers (TMs)

Other tasks as assigned by Chief Technical Officer (CTO) & Technical Managers (TMs) Device diagnostics and analysis



NSSF TRAINEE • NATIONAL SOCIAL SECURITY FUND(NSSF)

December 2019 - June 2020

Duties and Responsibilities

Operation of Social SSPAS and EDMS systems

Claim Enquiry, retrieval, opening and closing tasks and interpretation of SSPAS and EDMS workflow Data Cleaning (Data capture, sorting, matching and migration)

Customer Communication (Telephone Communication) Customer Care



IT Attaché • Ministry of Education (STATE DEPARTMENT FOR UNIVERSITY EDUCATION)

May 2016 - August 2016

Duties and Responsibilities

Maintenance and repair of power systems such as Backups

Network setups and administration

System specification, analysis, design and testing

Overseeing configuration of new ICT equipment verification, validation and certifying ICT equipment In-house training of users on ofice applications

Assisting in computer repairs and troubleshooting

Education



2012 - 2017

Multimedia University of Kenya

BSc. Computer Science



2012 - 2012

Alfran Computer College

certification in Computer Applications Packages

Skills

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- Laravel
- PHP MySQL
- WordPress
- React
- Network Support Hardware
- Troubleshooting Database Design
- and Development
- IP PBX & Telephony

Languages



- English Professional
- Swahili Professional

References

1.Mr. Samuel Maina

Technical Manager Safetrac Limited s.maina@safetrac.co.ke

Crater Automobile Limited, Nairobi

Mobile: 0720727587

2.Mr. Clement Odeka

ICT Oficer Ministry of education

P.O. Box 9583-00200, Nairobi

Mobile: 0722864926

3. Mrs. Carolyn Okul HRM

Manager NSSF

P.O. Box 30599-00100, Nairobi

Mobile: +254-020-2710552